A Finding Aid to the Robert Sperry Papers, 1951-2002, in the Archives of American Art AAA.sperrobe
Archives of American Art
- Gallery Files, 1962-2000, undated; Series 4; (Boxes 3-4; 0.8 linear feet)
  - Esther Saks Gallery, 1984-1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Following Sea, 1975-1980, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Gordon Woodside/John Braseth Galleries, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Great American Gallery (Gillette-Frutchey), 1982-1985, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Helen Drutt Gallery, 1981, 1991-1993, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Henry Gallery, University of Washington, 1961-1971, 1979-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hokin Gallery, 1990-1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Impressions Gallery, 1979-1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Joanne Rapp Gallery/The Hand and the Spirit, 1983-1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 15-17)
  - Kavesh Gallery, 1991, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Maple Hill Gallery, 1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Maveety Gallery (Lawrence Gallery), 1984-1993, undated (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
  - Netsky Gallery, 1982-1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Robert Kidd Gallery, 1981-1992, 1998, undated (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
  - Southwest Craft Center, 1985-1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Sylvia Ullman's American Crafts, 1975-1979, 1988, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Wita Gardiner Gallery, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Project and Workshop Files, 1967-1996, undated; Series 5; (Box 4; 0.4 linear feet)
  Files in this series typically contain correspondence, expense lists, receipts, itineraries, notes, and printed material related to sculpture projects and workshops that Robert Sperry completed primarily during the 1980s and 1990s. Project files include public commissions, notably the King County Administration Building Mural Project, IBM Wall Project, and the SAFECO sculpture. Files are arranged chronologically by year.
  - "Profiles Cast Long Shadows" Film Project, 1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Anderson Ranch Arts Foundation Workshop, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - University of Iowa Workshop, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - "Ceramics 80" Workshop, 1980, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Georgia State University Workshop, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - National Council on Education for Ceramic Arts 1982 Panel Member, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Washington State Arts Commission Art in Public Places Program, 1981-1985 (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
  - Fraser Valley Potters Guild Workshop, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - IBM Wall Project, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - King County Administration Building Mural Project, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Florida Craftsmen Conference Workshop, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - National Council on Education for Ceramic Arts Conference '88: "East Meets West,", 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - "Clay Revisions: Plate, Cup, Vase Clay Conference '89,", 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Kaplan Mural Commission, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - SAFECO Sculpture Project, 1988-1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 43-45)
  - Kerns Art Center Workshop, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Emily Carr College of Art & Design Lecture, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Hewlett-Packard Commission, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Saint Louis Galleria Mural Project, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 49-50)
  - Peoples State Bank Project, 1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - "Functional Pottery: Past, Present, Future" Symposium, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - National Council on Education for Ceramic Arts Conference '94: "Gumbo Ceramique,", 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - "Focus on Fire" Workshop, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Phoenix College Workshop, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - "Fahrenheit 96: Solid.Liquid.Solid" Symposium, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988-1989, 1996, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Writings, 1966-1990, undated; Series 6; (Box 5; 0.5 linear feet)
  This series houses writings by Robert Sperry and others, as well as Sperry's calendars. Writings by Sperry contain drafts for two articles published in art magazines. Also of interest is a family history he wrote which includes memories of his childhood on his family's farm, as well as many scanned photographs. This series also includes the screenplay, treatment and shooting script, and notes for "The Room" a film which Sperry never completed. Also found are many personal writings such as a brief journal, poetry, and miscellaneous notes. Writings by Others contain essays on art topics. Also included are various drafts of the catalog for the 1985 Robert Sperry retrospective. This sub-series is arranged alphabetically by author's last name.
  The Writings are organized into three subseries:
  6.1: Writings by Sperry, 1966-1990
  6.2: Writings by Others, 1986, undated
  6.3: Calendars, 1976-1984
  - Writings by Sperry, 1966-1990; 6.1
    - Article, "Abstractions in Black and White," Ceramics Monthly, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Article, The Studio Potter, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Family History, "Growing Up on the Prairies,", undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Journal, 1976-1978, 1982, 1990, undated (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
    - Notes, "The Room,", undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous, 1976, 1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Poetry, 1966-1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Screenplay, "The Room,", undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Treatment and Shooting Script, "The Room,", undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Writings by Others, 1986, undated; 6.2
    - Author Unknown, "The McCloud Gold Medal for Peter Voulkos,", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Author Unknown, "Patti Warashina's Little Worlds,", undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Author Unknown, "Robert Sperry,", undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Ball, F. Carlton, "Biographical Notes,", undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Kangas, Matthew, Catalog for "Robert Sperry: A Retrospective,", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
    - Krogstad, Karl, "Idiot Savant,", undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Romberg, Jim, "An Ancient Rerun,", undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Calendars, 1976-1984; 6.3
    - Calendars, 1976-1984 (Box 5, Folder 20-22)
- Scrapbook, 1955-1964; Series 7; (Box 5; 8 folders)
  This series contains one scrapbook which includes materials that Robert Sperry gathered between 1955 and 1964. The items are primarily related to exhibitions and newspaper articles featuring Sperry's artwork and include exhibition announcements and correspondence, photographs, and numerous press clippings.
  - Scrapbook, 1955-1964 (Box 5, Folder 23-30)
- Financial Records, 1961-1995, undated; Series 8; (Boxes 5-6; 1.0 linear foot)
  This series consists mainly of files for living and business expenses for Robert Sperry and his wife Patti Warashina from 1976 to 1984. Files include bills, receipts, and handwritten lists of expenses. Also found are files for records of earnings from the University of Washington, various lectures, and pottery sales. Other financial records include income tax returns, stocks, and the Myrtle Sperry Estate. Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject with miscellaneous items at the end.
  - Art Model Expenses, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Auto Expenses, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Books and Photograph Expenses, 1976-1984 (Box 5, Folder 33-41)
  - Entertaining and Gift Expenses, 1976-1984 (Box 5, Folder 42-45)
  - Household Expenses, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Income Tax Returns, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Karl Krogstad Payments, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Lecture Expenses and Earnings, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 49-52)
  - Lecture Expenses and Earnings, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
  - Myrtle Sperry Estate, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Patti's Trip to Japan, Expenses, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Personal Purchases, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Pottery Expenses, 1976-1984 (Box 6, Folder 9-20)
  - Pottery Sales, 1976-1984 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Shop Tool Expenses, 1978, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Stocks and IRA, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Trip to England and Italy, Expenses, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - University of Washington Wages, 1961, 1976-1984, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963-1995, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1975-1998, undated; Series 9; (Box 6; 0.2 linear feet)
  This series contains materials on a variety of topics and include all correspondence, printed material, notes, and other related documents. Files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Dolphin Defenders Membership, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Donation of Papers to the Archives of American Art, 1995, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Estate of Myrtle Sperry, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Estate of Zoe E. Sperry, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Exhibition Juror, Craft Art South 1981 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Exhibition Juror, "Vessels in Celebration,", 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Glaze Recipes and Notes, 1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - "Globalization and Modern Art" Cover Design, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Krogstad Studios Movie Investment, 1980-1985, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Multiple Myeloma, 1996-1997, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Patti Warashina's Japan Trip, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Request for Travel Funds, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Teaching Committee Reports, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Printed Material, 1955-2002, undated; Series 10; (Boxes 6-10; 3.4 linear feet)
  This series includes printed material and publications which mention Robert Sperry and his artwork as well as materials on events in the arts. There are numerous newspaper and magazine clippings on Sperry, his exhibitions and workshops, and other miscellaneous articles and images that he found interesting. Files of clippings about Sperry contain many reviews of his work. Also within this series are exhibition announcements and catalogs for Sperry and other artists, brochures for galleries and events, calendars of events, gallery guides, and newsletters. The series contains many art publications and a few non-art publications which mention Sperry and show his work, and books primarily on ceramics. This series is arranged alphabetically by type of material with miscellaneous items at the end.
  - Book, 2020 Vision: Health in the 21st Century, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Book, Art in Seattle's Public Places, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Book, Ceramics: A Potter's Handbook by Glenn C. Nelson, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Book, The Craftsman's World, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Book, Dimensions of Design, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Book, The First World Congress of Craftsmen, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Book, Jet Dreams: Art of the Fifties in the Northwest, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Book, Research in the Crafts, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Brochures, Miscellaneous, 1987-1988, 1992-1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Brochures, United Tile, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Brochures, Workshops, 1963-1965, 1975-1994, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Calendars of Events, 1966, 1987-1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Catalogs, Ceramic Supplies, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Catalogs, PONCHO Auction, 1985, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Catalogs, Workshops, 1968, 1978, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1956-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, Humorous, 1992-1993, 1997, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, Images, 1979, 1985-1988, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, Workshops and Exhibition Articles, 1955-1999, undated (Box 7, Folder 14-19)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1958-1996, undated (Box 7, Folder 20-26)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Robert Sperry, 1956-1969, 1976-2000, undated (Box 7, Folder 27-29)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Other Artists, 1957-2001, undated (Box 7, Folder 30-32)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Robert Sperry, 1956-1961, undated (Box 7, Folder 33-35)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Robert Sperry, 1962-1968, 1977-1997, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 1-20)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Other Artists, 1961-1966, 1982-1996, undated (Box 8, Folder 21-23)
  - Gallery Guides, 1986-1987, 1993-1999 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, The Arts, 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, Miscellaneous, 1957, 1961-1998 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Other, Arthur Efron, "Technology and the Future of Art,", undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Other, International Academy of Ceramics Bulletin, 1984, 1985, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Other, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation List of Fellowship Recipients, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Other, Matthew Kangas Published Writings, 1981-1982, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Publications, American Ceramics, 1983, 1986, 1991, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
  - Publications, American Craft, 1980-1987, 1990-1994 (Box 9, Folder 11-16)
  - Publications, Argus, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Publications, ARTFORUM, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Publications, Art Gallery International, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Publications, Art in America, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Publications, Arts Line, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Publications, Ceramic Art, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Publications, Ceramics: Art and Perception, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Publications, Ceramics Monthly, 1980-1987, 1990, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - Publications, Craft Horizons, 1955, 1960, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 27-30)
  - Publications, Creative Crafts, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Publications, Design Quarterly, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Publications, Miscellaneous (Non-Art), 1982, 1987, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Publications, NCECA Journal, 1982-1983, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 34-35)
  - Publications, New Art Examiner, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Publications, The Studio Potter, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Publications, Sunset, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Publications, Surface, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Publications, Vanguard, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Reports, "Art in the Embassies Program Progress,", undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Reports, University of Washington Fortieth Biennial Report, 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Tool Instruction Manuals, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1966, 1986, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Photographs, 1963, undated; Series 11; (Box 10; 0.2 linear feet)
  This series contains photographs, negatives, and slides, mainly from Robert Sperry's stay in Japan in 1963 while making the film "Village Potters of Onda." Also found are photographs and negatives of Sperry, his family (first wife Edyth and son Van), and artwork by him and other artists. The slides include photos taken by Sperry in 1976 at Grayland State Park, Washington, and Palm Gardens, Florida, and in 1979 at an unidentified political event. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject with negatives and slides filed separate from photographs.
  - Artwork by Sperry, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Hiroshima Visit, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Japan, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Japanese Potters, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Other Artists, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Sperry and Family, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Sperry in the Studio, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Negatives, Henry Gallery Exhibition Pottery, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Negatives, Hiroshima Visit, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Negatives, Japan, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Negatives, Nature, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Negatives, Sperry and Family, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Negatives, Sperry in the Studio, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Negatives, Student Artwork, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Negatives, Unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Negatives, "Yanagihara,", circa 1963 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Slides, 1976, 1979, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Sketches and Drawings, 1984, undated; Series 12; (Box 10; 2 folders)
  This series contains sketches and drawings by Robert Sperry which do not appear to be related to his ceramic works. Also found is one small pen drawing by his wife, Patti Warashina.
  - Sketches and Drawings by Robert Sperry, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Drawing by Patti Warashina, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Motion Picture Films, circa 1963-1998, undated; Series 13; (Boxes 10-11; 1.5 linear feet)
  This series contains VHS, which feature two documentaries on Sperry at work in his studio, and reel-to-reel motion picture film of various sizes. The reel-to-reel film includes footage for Sperry's award winning films "Village Potters of Onda" and "Profiles Cast Long Shadows" as well as other short and experimental studies such as the animated film "Henry." Titles given to the films in this series are based on the titles and descriptions written on each reel. Materials are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - VHS, "Attitudes: Goal Setting for Achievement,", 1988 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - VHS, "Bob Sperry in the Studio" (Edited), 1987 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - VHS, "Bob Sperry in the Studio" (Uncut), 1987 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - VHS, "Highlights - 2nd Quarter 1991" SAFECO Promotional Video," (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - VHS, "Robert Sperry: A Northwest Master,", 1998 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - VHS, "Views & Visions in the Pacific Northwest: The Making of an Exhibition,", 1990 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - "Orig. Stills - Band - Fire,", undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - "Van - Motorbike,", undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - "A & B Exp. #100,", undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "A & B Printer Head, 'Breakfast',", undated (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
  - "Animated Drawing Experiments - Steve,", undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Art 129 Rep. & Var.,", undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Art 129 - Visual Ideas - Clay,", 1966 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - "Belly Dancer,", undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - "Caterpillar,", undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Celantano Painting,", undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - "Color Printing Exper. ABC,", undated (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
  - "Experimental Color Print,", undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "Familiar Thickets,", undated; (1 large reel, 1 small reel) (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
  - "Family,", undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - "Food Color,", undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "Hamada,", undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - "Henry Print 1 Tail,", undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - "Later Henry,", undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - "Mickey Guston 'Profiles' Segment,", undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - "Misc. Zip Print,", undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - "Neg. Outs 'Profiles',", undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - "Op. Track,", undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - "Original - Amus. Park Rides,", undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - "Original Cello-tak,", undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - "Original Driving - Freeway,", undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - "Original Footage for Design,", 1966 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - "Original Footage - No Work Print - 'Breakfast',", undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - "Original Outs 'Profiles' Amusement Park Skull,", undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - "Original Outs 'Profiles' Rape,", undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - "Original - Skull Waves at Deception Pass,", undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - "Prostitute Scene - 'Profiles',", undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - "Room,", undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - "Sound Track Tail 'Hey There Voyager',", undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Unlabeled, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - "Village Potters of Onda,", circa 1963 (Box 11, Folder 37)